{
    "tossups": [
        {
            "question": "Besides his treatise on the Divine Names, the most notable work by Pseudo-Dionysius the Areopagitediscusses these things. The phrase \"Grigori\" refers to some of these things that are heavily described inthe apocryphal Books of Enoch. First Corinthians 11 argues that, specifically because of these things,women should wear head coverings when praying or prophesying. Tertullian suggested these thingsare what created the gigantic Nephilim. In the Talmud, Elisha ben Abuyah declares that there are \"twopowers in heaven\" when he sees one of these things named Metatron. The book of Daniel mentions oneof these beings by name, saying he will help fight the princes of Persia and protect Israel. For 10 points,name these celestial figures that include Gabriel and Michael.",
            "answer": "angels [or archangels; or fallen angels; or Watchers; or mal'akhim; or Grigori until it is read]",
            "category": "Religion"
        },
        {
            "question": "In an aria by this composer, a solo trumpet imitates the melody sung by a bass soloist describing theraising of the dead during Judgment Day. He wrote an interlude for strings and two oboes that beginswith busy B-flat major violin arpeggios. Another of his pieces includes a third-act \"Dead March\" thatdepicts the funeral procession of Saul. A dotted rhythm underlines the words \"And all the peoplerejoiced\" in a choral piece by this composer that ends with cries of \"God save the King!\". This composerof Zadok the Priest wrote arias such as \"Ev'ry valley shall be exalted\" and \"For unto us a child is born\" forhis oratorio about Jesus Christ. For 10 points, name this composer of Messiah, which includes the\"Hallelujah\" chorus.",
            "answer": "George Frideric Handel [or Georg Friedrich Handel]",
            "subcategory": "Fine Arts Auditory",
            "category": "Fine Arts"
        },
        {
            "question": "In a play by this author, an aging bachelor delivers a lengthy rant about the emptiness and despairthat awaits a philandering tutor with whom his lost love has become involved. In an autobiographicalshort novel by this man, the narrator becomes infatuated with his neighbor, a girl who hits him on thehead with flowers. In that novel of his, the narrator's father is the secret lover of Zinaida. A charactercreated by this author of First Love duels with Pavel and dies after forgetting to cauterize a cut hesuffers while treating a typhus patient. In his best-known novel, the medical student Arkady Kirsanovbrings home his friend, the nihilist Bazarov. For 10 points, name this Russian author of A Month in theCountry and Fathers and Sons.",
            "answer": "Ivan Turgenev [or Ivan Sergeyevich Turgenev]",
            "subcategory": "Literature European",
            "category": "Literature"
        },
        {
            "question": "Though not an e-beam, this phenomenon causes cross-linking in negative semiconductor resists,making it harder to remove. Commercially, devices that produce this phenomenon most commonlyhave their lifespan quoted in terms of L70 and use cerium-doped YAG. The development of devicesthat produce this thing earned Nichia Corporation's Shuji Nakamura the 2014 Nobel Prize in Physics. Apopular remote sensing method that is a variation on radar is named for this thing. The chromaticity ofa source of this thing is quantified by the CCT, or correlated color temperature, which is a measure ofhow close the source matches a blackbody locus. August K\u00c3\u00b6hler, of Carl Zeiss, developed a new way touse sources of this thing in microscopy. For 10 points, name this phenomenon that is produced byspontaneous emission in LEDs.",
            "answer": "light [or photons; or subtypes of light, such as UV light, white light, or blue light; prompt on electromagnetic waves]",
            "subcategory": "Science Physics",
            "category": "Science"
        },
        {
            "question": "A \"gas-and-water Socialist\" with this surname proposed an \"unauthorized programme\" whichpromised every citizen \"three acres and a cow\" while serving as Mayor of Birmingham. Leo Amerygave a speech echoing Oliver Cromwell in which he told a man with this surname, \"In the name ofGod, go!\". That leader with this surname was told to \"sacrifice the seals of office\" during the \"NorwayDebate\". This is the surname of Stanley Baldwin's foreign secretary, who with Charles Dawes won the1925 Nobel Peace Prize for negotiating the Locarno Pact. A man with this surname presided over the\"phony war\" and proclaimed \"peace for our time\" after returning from Munich. For 10 points, give thissurname of a pro-appeasement prime minister who preceded Winston Churchill.",
            "answer": "Chamberlain [or Neville Chamberlain; or Joseph Chamberlain; or Austen Chamberlain]",
            "subcategory": "History British",
            "category": "History"
        },
        {
            "question": "This economist claimed that a world reserve currency from a country whose central bank controls itsinflation rates could act as an asymptotically ideal money, such as the euro. This economist's paper\"The Bargaining Problem\" highlighted the importance of anticipation in negotiations. He used theBrouwer fixed-point theorem, rather than the Kakutani theorem, to expand on the work of John vonNeumann  (NOY-mahn) and Oskar Morgenstern in showing that non-cooperative scenarios always haveat least one equilibrium. This subject of a biography by Sylvia Nasar names a scenario in which noplayer can improve their outcome by changing their strategy. For 10 points, name this pioneer of gametheory who names an equilibrium and was the subject of the book A Beautiful Mind.",
            "answer": "John Nash",
            "category": "Social Science"
        },
        {
            "question": "A naval arms race between these two countries in the late 19th century was sparked by theconstruction of the Captain Prat. A foreign minister from one of these two countries offered the USpermission to use Salta as a military base for a campaign against the other country during theBaltimore Crisis of 1891. Pope John Paul II mediated a conflict between these two countries through theAct of Montevideo. Neither of these countries are Spain, but following the Disaster of Rancagua, one ofthese countries regained its independence when an army marched over the mountains from the otherand won the Battle of Chacabuco. During the Beagle conflict, these two countries fought for controlover islands in Tierra del Fuego. For 10 points, name these two South American countries that, withBrazil, comprise the ABC powers.",
            "answer": "Chile AND Argentina",
            "subcategory": "History World",
            "category": "History"
        },
        {
            "question": "Late in his life, this hero loses his balance while helping a group of men move a large rock. His wifeis a golden-haired woman first seen riding a white horse across the ocean. This hero witnesses hisfather's castle in ruins, covered by moss and ivy, and is told that his father was a myth who neverexisted. He is instructed to never let his feet touch the ground, but falls off of his horse and ages threehundred years upon his return from T\u00c3\u00adr na n\u00c3\u201cg. His mother is turned into a deer by an evil druid. Thisson of Sadhbh  (\"syve\") narrates much of his father's adventures to Saint Patrick in a collection thatbecame the Fenian Cycle. For 10 points, name this son of Finn MacCool, an Irish bard to whom JamesMacpherson  (mc-FEER-sun) attributed many poems.",
            "answer": "Ois\u00c3\u00adn  (oh-SHEEN) [or Ossian]",
            "category": "Mythology"
        },
        {
            "question": "This poet requests that a Naiad \"cut your body into turquoise pieces\" in a poem that begins, \"You arethe daughter of the sea\". The speaker of a poem by this man commands, \"do not look for me, for I shallalready have forgotten you\". A poem whose speaker declares, \"I do not love you as if you were salt-rose, or topaz\", was written by this author of \"If You Forget Me\". The addressee of another of his poems\"swallowed everything, like the sea, like time\", leading the speaker to proclaim, \"In you everythingsank!\". The speaker bemoans, \"Love is so short, forgetting is so long\" in this author's \"Tonight I canwrite the saddest lines\". For 10 points, name this Chilean poet of Twenty Love Poems and a Song ofDespair.",
            "answer": "Pablo Neruda [or Neftali Ricardo Reyes Basoalto]",
            "subcategory": "Literature World",
            "category": "Literature"
        },
        {
            "question": "Precancerous lesions in this structure can be treated with conization techniques such as cold-kniferesection and LEEP. The normal process of ectropion results in squamous cell invasion in thisstructure's transformation zone, which is particularly susceptible to CIN. A small, circular opening inthis structure called the external os changes into a transverse slit as a result of parturition. The HeLa(hee-luh) cell line is derived from cancerous cells in this structure. This structure secretes thin mucus,having a similar consistency to egg whites, around ovulation. Dysplasia in this structure, such as thatcaused by HPV, can be detected with a Pap smear. For 10 points, name this structure connecting theuterus to the vagina that dilates during labor.",
            "answer": "cervix",
            "subcategory": "Science Biology",
            "category": "Science"
        },
        {
            "question": "This author wrote, \"Be not chimera of morning, half-man, half-star\" in a poem inspired by WilliamCarlos Williams's \"El Hombre\". One of this author's poems describes \"such novelties of the sublime,such tink and tank and tunk-a-tunk-tunk\". Another poem by this author describes houses that are\"haunted by white night-gowns\" and later tells of a sailor who \"catches tigers in red weather\". In hispoem \"A High-Toned Old Christian Woman\", this author declared that \"Poetry is the supreme fiction\",a phrase he reused in the title of one of his long poems. Another of his poems includes the line, \"Let bebe finale of seem\". For 10 points, name this modernist American poet of \"Disillusionment of TenO'Clock\" and \"The Emperor of Ice-Cream\".",
            "answer": "Wallace Stevens",
            "subcategory": "Literature American",
            "category": "Literature"
        },
        {
            "question": "Organic halides of this element are produced with a copper catalyst in the direct process. Synthesisof bonds between this element and carbon can be accomplished with the platinum-based Karstedt'scatalyst. Increased stability is conferred to carbo\u00c2\u00b7cations when an atom of this element is placed beta tothe hypovalent carbon. Alcohol protecting groups containing ethers of this element can be removedwith tert-butylammonium fluoride. NMR shifts are calibrated in reference to a tetramethylated form ofthis element. It can be purified by chemical vapor deposition through the Siemens process. Its oxide isused to pack chromatography columns and TLC plates, and is a commonly used desiccant  (DESS-ih-kuhnt) . Various trace compounds plus this element's oxide constitute most glass. For 10 points, namethis element used in most semiconductor wafers.",
            "answer": "silicon [or Si]",
            "subcategory": "Science Chemistry",
            "category": "Science"
        },
        {
            "question": "Segments of an interstate bridge were floated upriver from North Kingstown to this city as part ofthe Iway project. This city's Waterplace Park holds gatherings during which several fires are lit in acircular pattern just above the surface of the Woonasquatucket  (woo-NOSS-qua-tucket) River. A notablygigantic statue of a blue termite serves as a roadside attraction in this city. The Seekonk River meetsthis city's namesake river at Fox Point, a former hub of the Atlantic slave trade. This city's College Hillis home to the oldest Baptist church in the United States. This capital city lies at the northern end ofNarragansett Bay and was founded by Roger Williams. For 10 points, name this home of BrownUniversity and capital of Rhode Island.",
            "answer": "Providence, Rhode Island",
            "category": "Geography"
        },
        {
            "question": "Under the tutelage of Victor Bertin  (bare-TAN) , this artist made many small sketches called pochades(po-SHODS) that he rarely developed into full canvases. This artist painted a mother and her girls pickingshrubbery off a thin tree, next to a much larger tree casting a huge shadow on a lake, in his canvasSouvenir de Mortefontaine. He painted many views of the pond overlooking the property he inherited atVille-d'Avray. This artist painted an on-the-spot depiction of the Castel Sant'Angelo and St. Peter'scupola in his canvas View of Rome, produced on an 1825 trip to Italy, which also informed his paintingof a ruined Roman arch bridge at Narni. For 10 points, name this oft-forged French landscape artistwhose en plein air painting inspired the Impressionists.",
            "answer": "Camille Corot [or Jean-Baptiste-Camille Corot]",
            "subcategory": "Fine Arts Visual",
            "category": "Fine Arts"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Overland Relief Expedition rescued around 200 people working in this industry. Workers inthis industry often used a phrase combining the name of a city with the word \"sleighride\". GeorgePollard led a contingent of workers in this industry who resorted to cannibalism after an 1820 disasterdescribed in a Nathaniel Philbrick book. A failed plan to blockade Charleston Harbor involved fillingobjects used in this industry with stone. A prized product of this industry was spermaceti  (sperm-uh-SET-ee) , and another of its products was once a common ingredient in perfumes. This industry was a lifelinefor towns such as New Bedford and Nantucket. For 10 points, name this industry that harvestedambergris and oil, and was fictionalized in Moby Dick.",
            "answer": "whaling [or word forms; prompt on fishing]",
            "subcategory": "History Other",
            "category": "History"
        },
        {
            "question": "A battle ax, a cup, a yoke, and one of these objects fell from the sky and were claimed by Scythes,the ancestor of the Scythians. The nymph Myrmex was turned into an ant for claiming to have inventedthis object. Bo\u00c3\u00b6tes  (boh-OH-teez) was turned into a constellation for his ingenuity at handling this object.After encountering a man using this object while carrying a bag of salt, Palamedes tricked that man,Odysseus, into confirming that he was sane, by placing Telemachus in front of this object. Ae\u00c3\u00abtes  (ee-EE-teez) challenged Jason to capture two fire-breathing bulls, then to use one of these tools to create an areato place some dragon teeth. For 10 points, Demeter inspired Triptolemus to invent what tool so that hecould teach Greeks to prepare fields for planting?",
            "answer": "plows",
            "category": "Mythology"
        },
        {
            "question": "The speaker of this poem describes humanity as \"children afraid of the night who have never beenhappy or good\" and asks, \"Who can live for long in a euphoric dream?\" after mentioning \"blindskyscrapers\". This poem makes reference to \"exiled Thucydides\", who \"knew all that a speech can sayabout democracy\", and it declares a quotation about Diaghilev by Nijinsky to be universal. Its speakerposits that \"the windiest militant trash\" is not as crude as the normal human wish: \"not universal love,but to be loved alone\". It begins as the speaker sits in one of \"the dives on Fifty-Second street\", andfamously proclaims, \"We must love one another or die\". For 10 points, name this W. H. Auden poem,titled for the day on which World War II began.",
            "answer": "\"September 1, 1939\"",
            "subcategory": "Literature British",
            "category": "Literature"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the book The Eudaemonic Pie, Thomas Bass described how Norman Packard used an oscilloscopeand a trig formula in this general activity to help start a scientific community. A strategy in this activityis the origin of the statistical term \"martingale\" and involved doubling a certain quantity and stoppingafter a finite time. A random variable with infinite expected value in this activity is the subject of theSt. Petersburg paradox. Claude Shannon and Edward Thorp's original application of the Kelly criterionwas to this activity. A fallacy named after a practitioner of this activity states that people incorrectlybelieve that an event is less likely to happen after it has happened X times. For 10 points, a specificinstance of what general type of activity is described in Bringing Down the House, an account of cardcounting?",
            "answer": "gambling [or obvious equivalents, such as betting money or wagering money; anti-prompt on roulette]",
            "subcategory": "Science Math",
            "category": "Science"
        },
        {
            "question": "This institution once refused to return items, for which it paid a fifteen-talent guarantee, during thereign of \"the Benefactor\". The possessions of this institution were catalogued in the Pinakes composedby Callimachus. The \"charakitai\" were employed at this facility, which had a \"daughter\" institutionknown as the Serapeum. A fifty-man synodos organized this institution in 283 BC at the order ofPtolemy Soter, who founded it as part of the larger Mouseion. In the 4th century AD, it was closed bythe Coptic Pope Theophilus, and it was later burned, possibly by invading armies under 'Amr ibn al-'As. For 10 points, name this institution which collected seventy thousand papyrus scrolls as the centerof Hellenistic learning.",
            "answer": "Library of Alexandria [or Mouseion until it is read]",
            "subcategory": "History World",
            "category": "History"
        },
        {
            "question": "Isabelle Lavigne chronicled the social lives of practitioners of this dance in her documentary AtNight, They Dance. Small cymbals held between fingers, known as zils, often specify 9/8 rhythms in aregional variant of this dance. Its common Western name was coined to describe the variant practicedby the Ouled Na\u00c3\u00afl  (OO-led NILE) tribe. Elements from hip hop and flamenco appear in the Westernized\"Tribal Fusion\" style of this dance. Common moves in this style of dance include the \"Figure 8\" and the\"shimmy\". Performers of this type of dance generally wear a skirt below a sequin-decorated fitted beltand bra, and sometimes carry a veil. For 10 points, name this type of Middle Eastern dance whoseperformers move their hips and exposed midriffs.",
            "answer": "belly dance [or Turkish oriental dance; or Raqs Sharqi; or Raqs Beledi; prompt on hoochie coochie dance]",
            "subcategory": "Fine Arts Other",
            "category": "Fine Arts"
        },
        {
            "question": "A race for this legislative position is much of the focus of the book Means of Ascent. That race for thispost featured an injunction stayed by Hugo Black at the behest of Abe Fortas, thwarting the desire ofCoke Stevenson to win this position. While holding this position, a man said \"Jack Kennedy was afriend of mine\" before telling Dan Quayle \"you're no Jack Kennedy\" during the 1988 vice-presidentialdebates. A man was nominated for this position in a 1948 primary that he won by 87 votes, giving himthe nickname \"Landslide\". That man, while in this position, used his \"The Treatment\" intimidationtechnique to convince fellow legislators to vote his way. For 10 points, name this legislative positionheld in the 1970s by Lloyd Bentsen and from 1949 to 1961 by Lyndon Johnson.",
            "answer": "Senator from Texas [prompt on Senate Majority Leader; prompt on Senator]",
            "subcategory": "History American",
            "category": "History"
        },
        {
            "question": "[missing]",
            "answer": "[missing]",
            "subcategory": "Literature American",
            "category": "Literature"
        }
    ],
    "bonuses": []
}